Just what is Intelligent Explorer? For your safety, you really need to know 


I recently hit, by mistake, what I thought was an Explorer upgrade option.  It turned out to be a pop-up appearing legitimate but really was not. It uploaded a product called Intelligent Explorer on my machine.  What a nightmare! 

I did some research on the web and found messages like this one from a BullGuard Antivirus Forum, 

"PLEASE HELP!!!  I HAVE A SPYWARE, TROJAN AND HIJACKER ON MY COMPUTER.  I HAVE RUN BULLGUARD, CWSHREDDER AND AD-AWARE.  ALL HAVE PICKED UP THE VIRUSES AND SAID THAT THEY HAVE BEEN MOVED/REMOVED BUT WHEN I LOG ONTO THE INTERNET THAT DAMN INTELLIGENT EXPLORER TOOLBAR IS SHOWING"

Another message from spywareinfo Forum goes something like this:

"Hey I'm having issues with something called Internet explorer toolbar - Intelligent explorer. I can’t find a way to remove it from my comp and I really don’t want to reinstall windows. I've used spybot, ad-ware, and cw shredder but nothing seems to work."

It appears that Intelligent Explorer allows other software to be downloaded to your machine and this is where the problem occurs. What is even more remarkable is that by downloading Intelligent Explorer, their license grants them the right to install software add-ins on your computer at their will.  Take a look at what the software license for Intelligent Explore says (go to http://www.ieplugin.com/terms.html to read it all):

"You grant to us the right, exercisable by us until you uninstall the Software or this agreement is otherwise terminated, to provide to you the Service of downloading and causing to be displayed advertising material on your computer, through ‘pop-up’ or other display while you use your browser.  You acknowledge and agree that installation of the Software may automatically modify toolbars and other settings of your browser.  By installing the Software you agree to such modifications."

The company, IBC incorporated, is incorporated in Belize.  I really can't believe this license!


One end user found highly objectionable pop-up advertisements generated by this software bundled with Intelligent Explorer in the form of extreme pornography. 

I have yet to break this. 


Intelligent Explorer is a plug-in, which can create a new home page, as well as start up and endless loop of pop-ups. You can remove the view bar, but then starting up Internet Explorer will cause it to reappear.  I asked some friends to help, and no one could tell me what to do.

This is what I did:

    I bought a copy of a program called XoftSpy and it removed the software. It took two scans and a reboot to do it. This is not an advertisement for this product.  They advertised it was free, which it was to run, but then I had to buy it to actually fix anything. It cost me $40 and I am sure that there are freeware products out there as well, but that is what ended the nightmare for me. Other spyware products I have seen out there include spybot, NoAdware, Spyware Eliminator, Pal Spyware Remover, and Spyware C.O.P.

    Let the buyer beware!
